

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER · POLYGLOT DEVELOPER

Plot no-131, Sector 16A, Nerul, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

🛘 (+91) 7021415633 | 🗷 sushantsawant007@yahoo.com | 🐐 https://www.kaggle.com/sushantsawant | 🖸 saint7007 | 🛅 sushantsawant007

"To solve a problem you need to know why you need to solve a problem"

Summary

Currently working as Senior Software Engineer at start-up company AMSYS Innovative Solutions. 7+ years experience specializing in the data engineering, backend development, architecting, and database modelling. Super nerd who loves Java, Scala and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Skills

Programming Java, Scala, Python, Node.js, Golang, Elixir, Erlang, R, C, C++

Data Engineering Spark, Flink, Kafka, Elasticsearch, Cassandra, Hive, Hadoop, AirFlow

Backend API Spring, Expressjs, GraphQL, Django, Flask, Phoenix, Microservices, Akka Http, Vert.x

DevOps AWS, Docker, Vagrant

Front-end Redux, React, HTML5, React Native

Languages Marathi, English, Hindi

Unorthodox Googling, Pomodoro Technique, Todo list for next day

Work Experience

Amsys Innovative Solution, Ltd.

Mumbai, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sep. 2019 - till Today

- Designed and developed OCR pipeline with AirFlow for image files stored in HDFS with Opencv python library, AWS textract and Google vision api and storing results in Elasticsearch for visualisation.
- Architected and implemented data lake solution for storing and querying real time EHR/EMR data with Hadoop, Hive, Spark and AirFlow for job management.
- Architected and implemented backend for US defence project(confidential) with microservice based architecture using reactive framework, Spring Webflux, Spring Cloud and AWS RDS (Postgres) all on Docker.
- Every minute cron for push notification with Firebase FCM with Akka actors based on Scala. Pushing around 1 lakh request a minute for project with US defence.

Bprise Analytics Pvt Ltd (Startup)

Mumbai, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ANALYTICS)

Aug. 2018 - Sep. 2019

- Improved existing streaming job by 5X, achieved throughput of around 250/sec on single core. This throughput is measured with one core, during kafka stream enrichment using Apache Flink. And database involved in overall pipeline were Elasticsearch, Redis, Cassandra with 4 node cluster.
- Implemented backend for a product which is on similar lines of google analytics with Spray Framework (Scala) for rest api based data ingestion and storing browser activity data in Elasticsearch via NSQ.
- Wrote elastic 100+ queries for reports for above two applications.
- Developed backend for a product for showing users the relevant advertisement using cookie sync using Spring boot, Redis, Cassandra and bit of javascript. Cassandra table modeling for reads.

Headway.ai (Stealth mode startup)

Bangalore, India

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Feb. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Developed and architected entire recruitment system with a recommendation engine for recruitment portal. Tech stack was python django,
 Spark, mongodb and postgres.
- Implemented resume parser which captures basic information using Standford NLP library.
- Developed recommendation engine for job description vs candidates based on very known collaborative filtering algorithm.

July 29, 2021 Sushant Sawant · Résumé 1

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Oct. 2015 - Nov. 2017

 Lead team and developed web application using Spring Java and Oracle. All transactions like NEFT,RTGS etc from bank with Core Banking Server where handled.

- Implemented a middle ware for PIN code encryption/decryption using Triple Des and RSA for mobile app and CBS for largest financial institution in India. Received lots of recognition for same.
- Developed a python flask web application and was given R code of calculating credit risk score by third party company with Client, since R being not production ready converted same into python code.

Blobcity iSolutions Pvt. Ltd (Startup)

Mumbai, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Oct. 2014 - Oct. 2015

- · Implemented B-tree based indexing for our own custom built ACID compliant NOSQL database.
- · Developed XMPP based Chat Server in Erlang with additional features encryption of messages and storing in database.
- Developed a dummy trading platform with NSE real data 6 minutes delay. (Scala, Java, Cassandra, BlobcityDB)

WorkJapan (Japanese startup)/ Junior Developers in US

Remote

FREELANCE DEVELOPER

Jan. 2019, Jun. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Developed Job Recommendation engine(Apache Spark, Python).
- Developed application that derives patterns from URL visits by customer i.e click events. Implemented GBIDE algorithm which works on tree
 pruning based search.
- Developed a Pyspark based job to match daily data from Oracle with summarised data. To check the delta in amount across all over.
- Elixir based web application with Phoenix and Ecto.
- Developed R script from algorithm, for IBM Watson. Input data had observation from scientific experiment. Read data from csv and integration.

Writing.

Technical Random Snippet

https://saint007code.blogspot.com/

WRITER

· Adding code snippet which I did not found easily.

Program Committees in Engineering

2012 Organiser & Co-director, Code competitions for Computers Department

India

2013 **Organizer & Co-director**, Inter College Science Paper Competition

India

Education

MU(Mumbai University)

Mumbai, India

Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

B.E. IN Information Technology Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2010

Aegis School of Business, Data Science and Telecommunication

Mumbai, India

EXECUTIVE PG PROGRAM IN DATA SCIENCE AND BIG DATA IN ASSOCIATION WITH IBM

Jun. 2018 - Jun. 2019